In this video, we're going to look at
how to pay vendors in Dynamics SL and
compare that to the experience of paying
vendors in Dynamics 365 Business
Central.
In SL, navigate to accounts payable.
Then, under processes, select payment
selection.
In payment selection, keep the default
period, account, and payment criteria.
Click down in the grid and PV on the
reference number field. Note the list of
vouchers available for payment.
Now, let's see how we can pay vendors in
Business Central.
Business Central allows you to easily
create payment journals and suggest the
vendors to pay based on criteria you've
defined.
Like SL, let's take a closer look at
creating vendor payments.
I'll click on the search icon and type
in payment journals. Based on the search
results, I can then select payment
journal.
Under prepare,
I'll select suggest vendor payments.
The suggest vendor payments wizard
opens.
I can select previously saved defaults
so that I don't need to re-enter
information each time I create vendor
payments.
The last payment date
is how I can indicate that we want to
pay invoices due on or before that date.
And we've also indicated to include any
available payment documents.
Now, let's click okay and have Business
Central suggest the list of payments
based on the criteria we've entered.
In this list, you can see the system has
created several payments for my vendors.
I currently have the system set to
create one payment per invoice. However,
in a moment, we'll look at how we can
change that setting.
Here, I can see the amounts of the
payments and the invoices
they're applied to. It looks like this
payment run will come to a little over
$30,000.
By using the vendor priority
functionality in Business Central,
BC will suggest payments to ensure that
we're paying our high priority vendors
first.
To see the vendor priority, let's open
the vendor card.
In the vendor card, I can go under the
payments area and see the priority. The
lower the number, the higher the
priority.
We see Worldwide Imports is set to
priority one.
Now, let's go back and run a payment
again.
Paying only our high priority vendors.
First, I'm going to select all my
payments so I can delete them and then
regenerate them.
Back under the suggested vendor
payments, I'm now going to select the
option to use vendor priority.
I'm also going to type in that we want
to pay $20,000 towards our vendor
invoices for the month. We will then
choose to summarize per vendor to create
one payment per vendor.
Now, you can see the system has reduced
the number of payments to only our
priority one vendors.
Through vendor priority and suggested
payments, Business Central helps
streamline paying your most strategic
vendors and gives you better control of
your cash flow.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.